Erwin Chargaff Papers 1929-1992 Mss.B.C37
American Philosophical Society
- Series Ia. Correspondence, 1949-2002; 5 boxes: 2.5 linear feet
  Incoming and outgoing manuscript and typewritten letters, telegrams, emails and postcards generated primarily during the latter part of Chargaff's life, although there is correspondence from other years as well. These papers were kept separate from the original Series I because there is little overlap with Chargaff's correspondents in Series I. Series Ia is arranged identically to Series I except that (a) correspondents with less than five leaves are filed together in a general file under the letter of their last name, for example, "B - Miscellaneous," except for certain letters predating the 1987 accession which were kept in item level files; and (b) correspondence with correspondents having a file in the original Series I has been removed to those files. Correspondents during this period of Chargaff's life included artists, philosophers, and writers as well as individuals who responded to his writings against genetic engineering. Most of this series is written in German.
  Significant correspondents in Series Ia include:
  Hargattai, Istvan Hofer, Michael Kuehn, Simone Leistikow, Dr. K. U.
  - A - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1990-2002 (Box 116)
  - Albus, Anita, 2000-2001 (Box 116)
  - Autograph Requests, 1986-2000 (Box 116)
  - B - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 116)
  - The Banbury Center, 1999-2002; Banbury Center. (Box 116)
  - Bauer, Anton, 1997-1998 (Box 116)
  - Berrish, Ingo, 2000 (Box 116)
  - Birkmayer, Florian, 2000 (Box 116)
  - Boch, Gudrun, 2001; Boch, Gudrun, 1944- (Box 116)
  - C - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987-2002 (Box 116)
  - Conzett and Huber, 1955; Conzett and Huber. (Box 116)
  - D - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986-2002 (Box 116)
  - Dahl, Jurgen, 1998-2001; Dahl, Jürgen (Box 116)
  - Dessauer, Maria, 1999-2000 (Box 116)
  - Deutscher Hochschul-Verband, 1989-2000; Deutscher Hochschulverband. (Box 116)
  - Deutsches Literaturachiv, 1993-2000; Deutsches Literaturarchiv. (Box 116)
  - Dex, Norbert, 1998-1999 (Box 116)
  - Duesberg, Peter, 1988-1991 (Box 116)
  - Dunsch, Boris, 1998-2000 (Box 116)
  - E - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988-2001 (Box 116)
  - Europa Verlag, 1949; Europa Verlag. (Box 116)
  - F - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987-2001 (Box 116)
  - Frankfurter Allgemeine, 1999-2001; Frankfurter Allgemeine. (Box 116)
  - Frankfurter Rundschau, 1998-2000; frankfurter rundschau. (Box 116)
  - G - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988-2001 (Box 116)
  - Gaul, Ewald, 1974; Gaul, Ewald, 1919- (Box 116)
  - Geigenmuller, Hans, 1988 (Box 116)
  - Gobl, Anny, 1988-2000; Göbl, Anny (Box 116)
  - H - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975, 1986-2002 (Box 116)
  - Hargattai, Istvan, 1991-1998 (Box 117)
  - Harms, Ingeborg, 1999-2000 (Box 117)
  - Hasenkamp, Holger, 1999-2002; Hasenkamp, Holger G. (Box 117)
  - Heeger, Hellmut, 1996-2000 (Box 117)
  - Henlein, Lore, 1984-1988 (Box 117)
  - Hermann Editeurs des Science et des Arts, 1972; Hermann Editeurs des Science et des Arts. (Box 117)
  - Herold, Hannelore, 1991-2000 (Box 117)
  - Hlavka, Gertrude, 2000-2001 (Box 117)
  - Hofer, Michael, 1998-2002; Hofer, Michael, 1966- (Box 117)
  - Hopp, Vollrath, 1999-2002 (Box 117)
  - Humboldt Universitat zu Berlin, 1990-1991; Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin. (Box 117)
  - I - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991-2001 (Box 117)
  - Invitation for Books, 1988-1994 (Box 117)
  - Invitation to Lectures I, 1988-1991 (Box 117)
  - Invitation to Lectures II, 1988-1991 (Box 117)
  - Invitation to Lectures III, 1989-1991 (Box 117)
  - J - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986-2001 (Box 117)
  - Jungk, Peter Stephan, 1998-2000; Jungk, Peter Stephan, 1952- (Box 117)
  - K - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988-2002 (Box 118)
  - Kalka, Joachim, 2000-2001 (Box 118)
  - Kappacher, Walter, 1998-2002; Kappacher, Walter, 1938- (Box 118)
  - Klestil, Thomas, 2000; Klestil, Thomas, 1933- (Box 118)
  - Klett-Cotta, 1997-2001; Klett-Cotta. (Box 118)
  - Monika Kraemer, 1999-2000; Kraemer, Monika, 1961- (Box 118)
  - Krieger, Hans, 2001-2002 (Box 118)
  - Kronigl, Roland, 1998-2001 (Box 118)
  - Kuehn, Simone, 1999-2001; Kühn, Simone (Box 118)
  - Kurschner Deutscher Literatur Kalender, 1998-2002; Kurschner Deutscher Literatur Kalender. (Box 118)
  - L - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987-2001 (Box 118)
  - Lanka, Stefan, 1997-1998; Lanka, Stefan, 1963- (Box 118)
  - Leistikow, K. U., 1997-2002; Leistikow, Klaus Ulrich, 1929- (Box 118)
  - Lessing, Kolja, 1998-2002 (Box 118)
  - Literary Agents, 1982-1995 (Box 119)
  - Litzmann, Johanna, 1998 (Box 119)
  - Low zu Steinfurth, Heinke, 1999-2001 (Box 119)
  - M - Miscellanous Correspondence, 1987-2001 (Box 119)
  - Maddox, Brenda, 1999 (Box 119)
  - Magistrat der Stadt Wien, 1990, 2000; Magistrat der Stadt Wien. (Box 119)
  - Mei del Testa, Alberto, 1987-2000 (Box 119)
  - Meider, Wolfgang, 1998, 2000 (Box 119)
  - N - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986-2002 (Box 119)
  - Ninetieth Birthday "Neunzigster", 1995 (Box 119)
  - O - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 119)
  - P - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986-2002 (Box 119)
  - Pieper, Franz, 1998-2001 (Box 119)
  - Pini, Joachim, 1999-2000 (Box 119)
  - Plozza Family, Bulk, 1998-2000; 1989, 1998-2000; Plozza (Box 119)
  - Pyke, David A., 1991 (Box 119)
  - Q - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1990, 2000 (Box 119)
  - R - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988-2001 (Box 119)
  - Radio and TV, 1987-2001 (Box 119)
  - Reitmeier, Henner, 1998 (Box 119)
  - Reuther, Karl Helmut, 1999-2000 (Box 119)
  - S - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986-2002 (Box 119)
  - Scheidewege, 1994-2002; Scheidewege. (Box 119)
  - Schwilk, Heimo, 2000-2001 (Box 119)
  - Sinn Und Form, 1991, 1998; Sinn Und Form. (Box 120)
  - Sinzinger, Ebba, Bulk, 1998-2000; 1995, 1998-2000; Ebba Sinzinger (Box 120)
  - Statistches Landesamt Berlin, 1989-1990; Statistches Landesamt Berlin. (Box 120)
  - Stewart, Walter, 1986-1988 (Box 120)
  - Symmetry, 1989-1990; Symmetry. (Box 120)
  - Szanto, Tibor, 1986-1987 (Box 120)
  - T - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986-2002 (Box 120)
  - Technische Universitat Berlin, Bulk, 1987-1991; 1987-1991, 2000; Technische Universität Berlin. (Box 120)
  - Teschke, Holger, 1998-2000; Teschke, Holger, 1958- (Box 120)
  - Trapp, Sebastian, 1998-2001 (Box 120)
  - U - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987-2000 (Box 120)
  - Unidentified, Bulk, 1997-2000; 1958, 1997-2000 (Box 120)
  - Unsolicited Correspondence, 1988-1995 (Box 120)
  - V - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 120)
  - Verlag der Arche, 1949; Verlag der Arche. (Box 120)
  - W - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986-2001 (Box 120)
  - Wasserman, Otmar, 1999-2000 (Box 120)
  - Weber, Doris, 1999-2000 (Box 120)
  - Weirich, Dieter, 1998-2000; Weirich, Dieter, 1944- (Box 120)
  - Wendt, Siegfried, 1998-2001; Wendt, Siegfried, 1940- (Box 120)
  - Wills, Peter, 1988-1999 (Box 120)
  - Wollschlager, Hans, 1999-2002 (Box 120)
  - Wulffen, Barbara von, 1998-2002; Wulffen, Barbara von, 1936- (Box 120)
  - die Zeit, 1986-1989; die Zeit. (Box 120)
  - X, Y, Z - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1990-2002 (Box 120)
  - Klett-Cotta Christmas Poster, 1987 (Box 157 (OVERSIZED))
- Series IIa. Grants, 1930-1982; 3.5 linear feet
  Applications, reports, correspondence, and expenditure statements for various agencies which granted Chargaff research money for his laboratories at Columbia University and at Roosevelt Hospital. The folders are arranged alphabetically by title. The American Cancer Society, the Office of Scientific Research and Development, and the United States Public Health Service account for a significant portion of this series. The earliest item in this series is a 1930 report to the Carnegie Corporation.
  - American Cancer Society, Inc. (Box 61)
    American Association for Cancer Research
    Haywood, Anne Mowbray
    See also Ser.I, American Cancer Society, Inc.
    - Folder #1, 1946-1948 (Box 61)
    - Folder #2, 1949-1950 (Box 61)
    - Folder #3, 1951-1953 (Box 61)
    - Folder #4, 1954-1956 (Box 61)
    - Folder #5, 1957-1961 (Box 61)
    - Folder #6, 1962-1963 (Box 61)
    - Folder #7, 1964-1965 (Box 62)
    - Folder #8, 1966-1967 (Box 62)
    - Folder #9, 1968-1970 (Box 62)
    - Folder #10, 1971-1976 (Box 62)
  - American Heart Association, 1961, 1963 (Box 62)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1930, 1937 (Box 62)
  - Committee on Medical Research, 1942-1945 (Box 62)
  - Damon Runyon Memorial Fund, 1950-1954 (Box 62)
  - Ford Foundation, 1956 (Box 62)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1944-1970 (Box 62)
  - Irma T. Hirshl Trust, 1972 (Box 62)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 1975 (Box 62)
  - Life Insurance Medical Research Fund, 1948-1965 (Box 63)
  - Lilly Research Laboratories, 1952-1955 (Box 63)
    Van Slyke, Donald D.
  - Josiah Macy Jr. Foundation, 1945 (Box 63)
  - John and Mary R. Markle Foundation, 1938-1947 (Box 63)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1979-1980 (Box 63)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1969-1982 (Box 63)
    See also Ser.IIa, United States Public
  - National Science Foundation (Box 63)
    - Folder #1, 1954-1962 (Box 63)
    - Folder #2, 1970-1978 (Box 63)
  - New York Heart Association, Inc., 1959-1967 (Box 63)
  - Nutrition Foundation, Inc., 1942-1951 (Box 63)
    Eisenhower, Dwight D.
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development (Box 63)
    See also Ser.I, Columbia University
    See also Ser.IIa, Committee on Medical Research
    - Folder #1, 1942-1943 (Box 63)
    - Folder #2, 1943-1944 (Box 64)
    - Folder #3, 1945-1947 (Box 64)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development. Circulars, 1943-1945 (Box 64)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development. Reports by Chargaff--Drafts, 1942-1945 (Box 64)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development. Reports by Chargaff--Final, 1942-1945 (Box 64)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development. Reports by Others (Box 64)
    - Folder #1, 1944 (Box 64)
    - Folder #2, 1944-1945 (Box 64)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development. Summaries of reports by Others (Box 64)
    - Folder #1, 1944 (Box 64)
    - Folder #2, 1945 (Box 64)
    - Folder #3, 1945 (Box 64)
    - Folder #4, 1945-1946 (Box 64)
  - Fannie E. Rippel Foundation, 1970 (Box 64)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1950-1965 (Box 64)
  - Unidentified, 1936-1940, n.d. (Box 64)
  - United States. Atomic Energy Commission, 1965 (Box 64)
  - United States. Office of Naval Research, 1950-1957 (Box 64)
  - United States Public Health Service (Box 65)
    See also Ser.IIa, National Institutes of Health
    - Folder #1, 1946-1948 (Box 65)
    - Folder #2, 1949-1951 (Box 65)
    - Folder #3, 1952-1954 (Box 65)
    - Folder #4, 1955-1958 (Box 65)
    - Folder #5, 1959-1960 (Box 65)
    - Folder #6, 1961-1963 (Box 65)
    - Folder #7, 1964 (Box 66)
    - Folder #8, 1965-1966 (Box 66)
    - Folder #9, 1967-1968 (Box 66)
    - Folder #10, 1969-1970 (Box 66)
    - Folder #11, 1971-1976 (Box 66)
  - Weintraub Foundation, 1970 (Box 66)
  - Williams-Waterman Fund for the Combat of Dietary Diseases, 1947-1948 (Box 66)
- Series IIb. Subject files, 1940-1984; 1.5 linear feet
  Programs, brochures, newspaper and magazine clippings (including some reviews of Chargaff's books), reports, meeting minutes, lists of books ordered by Chargaff (folder labeled "Books") and places visited by Chargaff (folder labeled "Travel"), various versions of Chargaff's curriculum vitae, trip itineraries, and material regarding laboratory administration. The largest portion of Series IIb deals with the National Academy of Science and mainly contains meeting minutes and reports. The folders are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1963-1971 (Box 67)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1955 (Box 67)
  - ARTORG, 1958 (Box 67)
  - Bertner Foundation Lecture and Award, 1965 (Box 67)
    See also Ser.VI, Bertner Lecture and Award
  - Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 1954-1958, 1968-1971 (Box 67)
  - Bone Marrow Transplantation and Chemical Radiation Protection Conference, 13 Aug. 1958 (Box 68)
  - Books (Box 68)
    - Folder #1, 1943-1962 (Box 68)
    - Folder #2, 1963-1983 (Box 68)
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1951 (Box 68)
  - Clippings, 1966-1983, n.d. (Box 68)
    Some In German
  - Central Research Unit, 1964 (Box 68)
  - Columbia University, 1961-1962 (Box 68)
  - Columbia University. Government Contract Division, 1940-1945 (Box 68)
  - Curriculum Vitae--Chargaff, [193-], 1960, 1965, [1983] (Box 68)
  - The Double Helix by James D. Watson, 1968-1973, n.d. (Box 68)
  - Essays on Nucleic Acids, 1958-1969, n.d. (Box 68)
  - Faraday Society, 1953, 1956 (Box 68)
  - H.P. Heineken Prize, 1964 (Box 68)
  - Heraclitean Fire, 1978-1981 (Box 68)
    See also Ser.IV, Rota, Gain-Carlo, Heraclitean Fire by Erwin Chargaff--Review
  - India. All India Institute of Medical Sciences, 1958-1959 (Box 69)
    See also Ser.I, India. Embassy
  - International Botanical Congress, 1964 (Box 69)
  - International Congress of Biochemistry, 1957-1970 (Box 69)
  - Japan trip, 1958 (Box 69)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1951, 1956 (Box 69)
  - Laboratory Administration, 1947-1984, n.d. (Box 69)
  - Meyer Lasker Award, 1960, 1962, 1970 (Box 69)
  - Charles Leopold Mayer Prize, 1963-1964 (Box 69)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1963-1976 (Box 69)
    Business; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Honors; National Academy of Sciences; Publication
    - Folder #1, 1963-1966 (Box 69)
    - Folder #2, 1967-1976 (Box 69)
  - National Academy of Sciences. Minutes, 1965-1969 (Box 69)
    Business; National Academy of Sciences -- Meeting minutes
  - National Academy of Sciences. Reports (Box 69)
    National Academy of Sciences -- Reports; Publication
    - Folder #1, 1966-Apr. 1967 (Box 69)
    - Folder #2, Aug. 1967 (Box 70)
    - Folder #3, 1968 (Box 70)
  - National Research Council, 1951-1954 (Box 70)
  - Florence Nightingale Hospital, 1941 (Box 70)
    See also Ser.I, Florence Nightingale
  - The Nucleic Acids, 1953-1958 (Box 70)
  - The Nucleic Acids--Reviews, 1955-1957 (Box 70)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory (Box 70)
    See Ser.IIb, Union Carbide Corporation
  - Picker Corporation, 1969 (Box 70)
  - Recent Studies on Nucleic Acids, 30-May-52 (Box 70)
  - Recombinant DNA, 1976-1977 (Box 70)
    See also Ser.I, Adler, Frederick
    See also Ser.I, Apsell, Paula S.
    See also Ser.I, Christensen, Gerald
    See also Ser.I, DeNike, L. Douglas
    See also Ser.I, Ehrenfeld, David W.
    See also Ser.I, Friends of the Earth
    See also Ser.I, Garb, Solomon
    See also Ser.I, Goldman, Dexter S.
    See also Ser.I, Hardin, Garrett
    See also Ser.I, Krcmery, V.
    See also Ser.I, Kusch, Polykarp
    See also Ser.I, Lefkowitz, Louis J.
    See also Ser.I, Loeb, Lawrence A.
    See also Ser.I, Mislow, Kurt
    See also Ser.I, Paplauskas, Leonard
    See also Ser.I, Pederson, Thoru
    See also Ser.I, Peoples Business Commission
    See also Ser.I, Rapp, Fred
    See also Ser.I, Rushmer, Robert F.
    See also Ser.I, Sadowski, Tad
    See also Ser.I, United States. Environmental Protection Agency
    See also Ser.I, Walter, Donald O.
    See also Ser.I, Weizenbaum, Joseph
    See also Ser.I, Wright, Susan
  - Society for the Study of the Blood, n.d. (Box 70)
  - Society of Cellular Physiology, [195-] (Box 70)
  - Students, 1956-1971, n.d. (Box 70)
  - Symposium on Biophysics, 1956 (Box 70)
  - Travel, 1945-1984 (Box 70)
  - Union Carbide Corporation, 1948-1965 (Box 70)
  - Union Nationale Contre Le Cancer, 1950 (Box 70)
  - University of Michigan, 1956 (Box 70)
  - Weizmann Institute of Science, 1961-1963 (Box 70)
  - Yugoslavia Trip, Jun.-Jul. 1970 (Box 70)
- Series IIc. Subject Files, 1946-2002; 1 box: .25 linear feet
  Clippings (including reviews of Chargaff's books, transcripts of radio and TV appearances, and newspaper and magazine clippings) and rental agreements. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. Most of this series is in German.
  - Clippings, 1958-2002 (Box 121)
  - Columbia University, 1976; Columbia University. (Box 121)
  - Contracts, 2001 (Box 121)
  - H. P. Heineken Prize, undated (Box 121)
  - Humbolt University, 1990; Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin. (Box 121)
  - Klett-Cotta, undated; Klett-Cotta. (Box 121)
  - National Science Foundation, 1974 (Box 121)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, 1980 (Box 121)
    New York Academy of Medicine.
  - Nobel Prize, 1987 (Box 121)
  - Princeton University Bicenntial Chemistry Photograph, 1946 (Box 121)
  - Rental Agreements "Wohnsitzahme", 1974-1982 (Box 121)
  - Royal Netherlands Academy of Sciences, 1964 (Box 121)
  - Tubinger Initiative die geplante Bioethik-Konvention, 1998 (Box 121)
- Series III. Works by Chargaff, 1929-1989; 15.5 linear feet
  Chargaff's typewritten and handwritten outlines, preparatory notes, research, and drafts for articles, books, reviews, lectures, and tributes to colleagues. Also included for some works are galley proofs. For each work, the notes, drafts, and galley proofs are filed together. This series is arranged alphabetically by title. Chargaff assigned a number to almost every item of his extensive bibliography; these numbers, when available, have been marked in pencil in the upper left corner of each folder in Series III. A chronological list of Chargaff's works, complete with these numbers, is contained in Series III, in a folder marked "Bibliographies." Cross-references are given for photographs and reprints which appear in this series. The earliest materials in this series are galley proofs from 1929 for "Über die Katalytische Zersetzung Einiger Jodverbindungen" and "The Chemistry of the Lipoids of Tubercle Bacilli. V. Analysis of the Acetone-Soluble Fat." Many of the works are co-authored with students and colleagues. Articles which appeared in chapters in Voices in the Labyrinth: Dialogues Around the Study of Nature are filed separately by title. There are several series of articles, including "Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation" and "Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids."
  - 2-0-Methylribonucleosides Participating in Alkali-Resistant Sequences of Ribonucleic Acid, 5/15; Chargaff and Seiji Morisawa (Box 71)
  - Das Aceton-Lösliche Fett Der Timotheegrasbakterien, [193-]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 71)
  - Action of DNA Polymerase I of Escherichia Coli with DNA-RNA Hybrids as Templates, [1972]; Chargaff, John D. Karkas and Yiannis G. Stavrianopoulos (Box 72)
  - Action of Nucleotide Phosphotransferase of Escherichia Coli on Nicotinamide Riboside and Nicotinamide Mononucleotide, [1977]; Chargaff and Elinor F. Brunngraber (Box 72)
  - The Action of Periodic Acid on a Cyclohexose Osazone, [1948]; Chargaff and Boris Magasanik (Box 72)
  - The Action of Periodic Acid on Glucose Phenylosazone, [1947]; Chargaff and Boris Magasanik (Box 72)
  - Action of Ribonuclease on a Microsomal Ribonucleoprotein, [1959]; Chargaff and Harold T. Shigeura (Box 72)
  - Amphisbaena, n.d.; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 72)
  - Analyse Sérologique des Différentes Fractions Lipoidiques du BCG, [1935]; Chargaff and Werner Schaefer (Box 72)
  - Antagonism Between Tropolene and Colchicine in Rat Fibroblast Cultures, [1953]; Chargaff, Helena H. Benitez and Margaret R. Murray (Box 72)
  - Anticoagulants and Plasma Proteins, 6 Jan. 1941; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 72)
  - The Apurinic Acids from Deoxyribonucleic Acid Fractions, 5/8; Chargaff and Marion E. Hodes (Box 72)
  - Aspects of Nucleic Acid Fractionation, [1959]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 72)
  - Aspects of the Invariability of a Bacterial Ribonucleic Acid, 5/10; Chargaff and Anna Lombard (Box 72)
  - Aspects of the Nucleotide Sequence in Nucleic Acids, 5/17; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 72)
  - Aspects of the Stability of a Bacterial Ribonucleic Acid, [1958]; Chargaff, Jack Horowitz and Anna Lombard (Box 73)
  - An Assay of Ribonuclease H, Endoribonucleases, and Phosphatases, [1976]; Chargaff and Yiannis G. Stavrianopoulos (Box 73)
  - Bacterial Desoxypentose Nucleic Acids of Unusual Composition, [1950]; Chargaff, Stephen Zamenhof, George Brawerman, and Leonard Kerin (Box 73)
  - Bacterial Enzyme Preparations Oxidizing Inositol and Their Inhibition by Colchicine, [1951]; Chargaff and Robert E. Franzl (Box 73)
  - Base Composition of Deoxypentose and Pentose Nucleic Acids in Various Species, 5/9; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - Beating the Drum for Small Science, 6/4; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
    Unpublished
  - Beiträge zur Kenntnis der Chemischen Zusammensetzung Pathogener Bakterien, n.d.; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - Betrachtungen Über Desoxyribonukleinsäure Als Schablone Oder Text, [1968]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - Bibliographies, 2 folders; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
    Bibliographical matters; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, [193-]-[197-] (Box 73)
    - Folder 2, [197-] (Box 73)
  - The Biological Significance of Lipoproteins, 26 Aug. 1940; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - The Biological Significance of the Thromboplastic Protein of Blood, [1946]; Chargaff and Randolph West (Box 73)
  - Bitter Fruits from the Tree of Knowledge: Remarks on the Current Revulsion from Science, [1973]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - A Bleached Variant of Euglena Gracilis Showing a Doubling of the Content of Deoxyribonucleic Acid, 5/13; Chargaff, George Brawerman and Carole Ann Rebman (Box 73)
  - Building the Tower of Babble, [1974]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - Calculated Composition of a Messenger Ribonucleic Acid, 5/15; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - Cell Structure and the Problem of Blood Coagulation, [1945]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - Cellular Control Mechanisms and Their Uncoupling, 5/12; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
    Jesup Lecture III
  - Cerebroside Sulfuric Acids and Their Action in Blood Clotting, 9 Sep. 1937; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 73)
  - Changes in Protein and Ribonucleic Acid During the Formation of Chloroplasts in Euglena Gracilis, 5/11; Chargaff and George Brawerman (Box 74)
  - Characterization of Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids Through Stepwise Acid Degradation, [1957]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 74)
  - Chemical and Biological Properties of Nucleic Acids and Nucleoproteins--progress reports, 1952-1959; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 74)
  - Chemical and Immunological Properties of Fractions from Rickettsia Prowazeki, 5/26; Chargaff, Samuel C. Bukantz and Seymour S. Cohen (Box 74)
  - Chemical and Immunological Properties of the Various Fractions of the Bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG), 12 Apr. 1935; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 74)
    See also Ser.III, A Specific Polysaccharide from the
  - Chemical Composition of Bacterium Tumefaciens, [1936]; Chargaff and Michael Levine (Box 74)
  - Chemical Composition of the Nucleic Acids from Carcinomatous Human Liver and from Normal Human Tissue, 14 Mar. 1950; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 74)
  - Chemical Tumefaciens, 1 Apr. 1938; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 74)
  - Chemical Specificity of Nucleic Acid and Mechanism of Their Enzymatic Degradation, [1950]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 74)
  - Chemical Tumors in Plants and Their Significance, [193-?]; Chargaff and Michael Levine (Box 74)
  - The Chemistry and Biological Significance of Hydroxyketo Acids, [1946]; Chargaff and David B. Sprinson (Box 74)
    - Folder 1 (Box 74)
    - Folder 2 (Box 74)
  - Chemistry of Inositol, [1954]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 74)
  - The Chemistry of the Acyclic Constituents of Natural Fats and Oils, [1935]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 74)
  - The Chemistry of the Lipoids of Tubercle Bacilli. V. Analysis of the Acetone-Soluble Fat, 4/12; Chargaff and R.J. Anderson (Box 74)
  - Chromatographic Behavior of Analogues of the Nitrogenous Lipide Constituents, [1951]; Chargaff and Celia Levine (Box 74)
  - Chromatographic Separation of Desoxyribonucleotides in Minute Amounts, [1951]; Chargaff and David Elson (Box 74)